Guide to the Henry Draper Image Collection MC.230
New York University Archives
- Series VII. Lecture Presentation Support Images, 1863-1897, undated
  - Rowland's Apparatus, undated; cuid14762; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Two Painted Cats and Moon, undated; cuid14763; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14764; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14765; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14766; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Mg with Plate of Glass in Rays, undated; cuid14767; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14768; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14769; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Drawing of Solar Prominences, undated; cuid14770; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Spectrum, undated; cuid14771; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Chart of Pleicedes Showing Nebula Around Stars Taken with 8 inch Telescope, undated; cuid14772; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 14)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897.
  - Spectra, undated; cuid14773; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Bl. Lines Argus, undated; cuid14774; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - 434, undated; cuid14776; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Nova Normae and Nova Aurigae Spectra, undated; cuid14777; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - No. D3258 -- New Variable in Scorpius, undated; cuid14778; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Cluster in Centauri, undated; cuid14779; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - AZ 31 - New Variable in Scorpius, undated; cuid14780; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - D3091 -- The Southern Cross, undated; cuid14783; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Spectra of Alpha Canis Majoris, Alpha Canis Minoris, and Alpha Aurigae, undated; cuid14784; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 26)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Four prisms enlarged about thrice.
  - Spectra of Alpha Lyrae, Alpha Cygni, and Alpha Bootis, undated; cuid14785; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae, undated; cuid14786; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 28)
    Sample sent to Mrs. Draper December 12 1897. Spectra of Beta Persei and Beta Lyrae at full light time and at minimum. The difference in width of the lines. The disappearance of 1 line at minimum and the overlapping of the ends of the spectra may be real phenomena and require further study. A number of plates taken last night will probably settle these points. The other spectra represent the variables Beta Lyrae and Omicron Ceti. The differences in these types of variables is well shown by these spectra. One prism (?) enlarged three times.
  - Spectra of Alpha Cassiopeii, P. Cygni, and H.P. 1311, undated; cuid14787; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 29)
    Samples sent to Mrs. Draper December 23 1889.
  - Art History, undated; cuid14788; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14789; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14790; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14791; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14792; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 34)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14793; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14794; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14795; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14796; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14797; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14798; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14799; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14800; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14801; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14802; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14803; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14804; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - Art History, undated; cuid14805; Lantern slide (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Blank Slide, undated; cuid14736; Lantern slide (Box 32, Folder 105)
- Series VIII: Daguerreotypes, 1860, undated; x Linear Feet in 4 boxes.
  This series contains a Daguerreotype portrait of NYU alumnus, writer Cornelias Mathews; unknown object; 24 blank Daguerreotype sheets; and a glass cover.
  - Faint Circular Image, 1860; cuid14807; Daguerreotype plate (Box 35)
  - Daguerreotype Glass Cover, 19th century; cuid14870 (Box 10)
  - 24 Blanks for Daguerreotypes, undated; cuid14806 (Box 15)
    General
    Daguerreotype plates
  - Cornelius Mathews, undated; cuid14808; Daguerreotype (Box 36)
- Series IX. Document Reproductions, Memorial Images, 1845-1899; x Linear Feet in 3 boxes.
  This series includes images of the Henry Draper Memorial, a portrait of John Johnson, an insect, and reproductions of images of unknown documents.
  - Reproduction of a John Johnson Portrait, 1845; cuid14898; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Notes Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14886 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Insect Image, circa 1850-1899; cuid14887; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Document Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14888; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified Object Image, circa 1850-1899; cuid14894; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Illustration of Superior Vena Cava and Human Head, circa 1850-1899; cuid14893; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Document Reproduction -- "Chapter 7", circa 1890s; cuid14895; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Document Reproduction -- "Chapter 7", circa 1890s; cuid14896; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Unidentifed Document Reproduction, circa 1850-1899; cuid14897; Image on paper (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Henry Draper Memorial, undated; cuid2080; Glass plate (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Henry Draper Memorial, undated; cuid14564; Cardboard print (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series X. Original Storage Housing, 1915, undated; x Linear Feet in 4 boxes.
  This series contains boxes which had orginally held lantern slides and glass plate negatives in this collection.
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, March 1915; cuid14867; Wooden box (Box 27)
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, March 1915; cuid14868; Wooden box (Box 28)
  - Wooden Lantern Slide Box, undated; cuid14869; Wooden box (Box 29)
  - Wooden Cabinet for Glass Plate Negatives, undated; cuid14874 (Box 40)
    ID Number: 286. Description: containing spectral slides. Creator/Donor/Subject: Draper, Henry. Dimensions: 21w x 13d x 15.5h